A Guide to the American International Association for Economic and Social Development (AIA) FA079
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Photographs, 1946-1968, n.d.; 19.0 Boxes
  - Brazil
    - EMA, Bebedouro (Box 5, Folder 116)
      1. Discing machine drawn by light diesel tractordiscing equipment used on newly cleared areas. 2. EMA, Bebedouro, Brazil. Land being seeded with Sementes Agroceres hybrid corn. 3. EMA, Bebedouro, Brazil. Machinery used to seed corn. 4. EMA, Bebedouro, Brazil. Machinery used to seed corn. 5. EMA, Bebedouro, Brazil. Business end of TD-18 tractor. Isaacson Klearing dozer with detachable teeth, elevator control. 6. EMA, Bebedouro, Brazil. EMA Technical Director, Carl Schneider, explaining principle of terracing equipment used in soil conservation work. Terracing the land helps prevent soil erosion, keeps rain from washing away topsoil. 7. Land clearing operation in Bebedouro, Brazil, by EMA, farm mechanization company and affiliate of IBEC of which Nelson A. Rockefeller is president.
    - EMA, Jacarezinho (Box 5, Folder 117)
      8. Joao Toledo (left), manager, Jacarezinho EMA unitDr. Oscar Thompson, Commercial Manager EMA. 9. EMA, Jacarezinho, Brazil. 6:30 am morning line at Usina Jacarezinho. EMA's big clearing, stumping and plowing job keeps machines and crews in motion around the clock. After the night shift, tractors move to field base for cleaning, lubrication, fueling, and inspection. 10. Jacarezinho, Parana, 1/20/1949. EMA heavy duty tractor pushes fallen brush into windows at Usina Jacarezinho sugar plantation. 11. EMA. Intricate tree felling operation performed by Eliseo Alves de Lima, qualified after less than two months training by EMA, Jacarezinho. 12. Oscar Thompson, former commercial manager of EMA, now manager of a larger sugar fazenda between Ourinhos and Jacarezinho. 13. EMA. Plowing as well as clearing goes ahead after sundown on sugar plantation between Ourihnos and Jacarezinho. 14. EMA. TD-18 in a clearing operation on a fazenda near Jacarezinho carried out by EMA, an affiliate of the IBEC. 15. EMA. TD-18 in a clearing operation on a fazenda near Jacarezinho carried out by EMA, an affiliate of the IBEC. 16. EMA, Jacarezinho. Next stage of EMA operation at Usina Jacarezinho is plowing. Heavy disc equipment used on newly cleared areas. 17. EMA, Jacarezinho. Bunkhouse at Usina Jacarezinho - temporary home of EMA crew. 18. EMA, Jacarezinho. Worker's bunkhouse, Jacarezinho compound. 19. EMA, Jacarezinho. Stockroom control. Records are kept here of all parts used in Jacarezinho unit operations. 20. EMA, Jacarezinho. Parts building. 21. EMA, Jacarezinho. Parts building, interior. Heavy machine installations stored in room, background. 22. EMA, Jacarezinho. Well water for tractor cooling system. 23. EMA, Jacarezinho. Less than a week earlier land shown here was untillable waste. Stumps have been piled for drying and burning and entire acreage is prepared for more Brazilian sugar. 24. EMA, Jacarezinho. Less than a week earlier land shown here was untillable waste. Stumps have been piled for drying and burning and entire acreage is prepared for more Brazilian sugar. 25. EMA, Jacarezinho. Less than a week earlier land shown here was untillable waste. Stumps have been piled for drying and burning and entire acreage is prepared for more Brazilian sugar. 26. EMA, Jacarezinho. Less than a week earlier land shown here was untillable waste. Stumps have been piled for drying and burning and entire acreage is prepared for more Brazilian sugar. 27. EMA, Jacarezinho. EMA tractor drivers and maintenance crew at Usina Jacarezinho field base. 28. EMA, Jacarezinho. Farmall light tractor with harvester-binder. 29. EMA, Jacarezinho. Fuel drums here bear distinctive EMA markings and colors. 30. EMA, Jacarezinho. Fuel deposit. 31. EMA, Jacarezinho. Precision instruments, valuable small parts stored in this building. 32. EMA, Jacarezinho. Unit office. Manager Joao Toledo, right. 33. EMA, Jacarezinho. Parts building, an old barn remodeled. 34. EMA, Jacarezinho, Brazil. 6:30 am morning line at Usina Jacarezinho. EMA's big clearing, stumping and plowing job keeps machines and crews in motion around the clock. After the night shift, tractors move to field base for cleaning, lubrication, fueling, and inspection. 35. EMA, Jacarezinho. Cleaning platform for trucks and tractorsregion's deep mud and heavy dust make frequent, complete washing necessary routine. 36. EMA, Jacarezinho. Land being seeded with Sementes Agroceres hybrid corn. 37. Joao Toldeo, with AH Vandenberg Jr., with map showing area in which EMA operatesJoao Toledo, former manager of EMA's Jacarezinho unit, is now assistant to Carl Schneider, EMA manager. 38. EMA, Jacarezinho. Joao Toldeo, Brazilian assistant to EMA's managerformerly was manager of the Jacarezinho unit.
    - EMA, Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 118)
      39. 1,000,000-bushel grain elevator in the state of Sao Paulo, Brazil, serves centers of consumption and exportation in Ourinhos area. 40. Oscar Thompson, Commercial Mgr. of EMA instructing Brazilian tractor driver on his first day of work. International Harvester tractor of TD-14 type. 41. An EMA TD-9 tractor with bulldozer filling holes caused by erosion in a pasture near Mococa. 42. Section of a road ruined by erosion to be filled and leveled by EMA machines near Mococa. 43. Detail of machinery used for terracingEMA has introduced this equipment into Brazil. 44. No caption. 45. No caption. 46. No caption. 47. No caption. 48. No caption. 49. No caption. 50. No caption. 51. No caption. 52. No caption. 53. No caption.
    - HELICO (Box 5, Folder 119)
      1. HELICO, Brazil. Helicopters used in dusting operationstaken at Bauru, Brazil, 2/1949. 2. HELICO, Brazil. Bell Aircraft maintenance representative at Bauru, Brazil. 3. - 8. HELICO, Brazil. Helicopters used in dusting operationstaken at Bauru, Brazil.
    - SASA (Box 5, Folder 120)
      1. Homero Freitas, SASA manager, with A.H. Vandenberg, Jr. at sorting table. Sorting table permits ear corn to flow past workers well trained in elimination of all ears not suitable for seed. 2. Homero Freitas, SASA manager, center, explains tests of 36 hybrids at Santa Rita to agricultural writer Mario Mazzei. Isidro Zarate, fazenda foreman, right. 3. SASA town headquarters in Jacarezinho. Homero Freitas, SASA manager and office assistant. 4. Homero Freitas, SASA manager, inspecting corn at sorting table, which permits corn to flow past workers well trained in elimination of all ears not suitable for seed. Discarded ears are weighed back to the cooperators (farmers who sell their corn to SASA) and discounted from total of corn received. 5. No caption.
    - SAFAP, Agriculture (Box 5, Folder 121)
      1. No caption. 2. Newborn Duroc-Jeresyages one and ten days. 1949. 3. Common Sow with pigs. 4. Common Sow with pigs. 5. Excellent yield of Sementes Agroceres hybrid corn. 6. San Carlos. Entrance to the breeding farm. 7. Field feeding shed for unweaned litters. 8. Farrowing house, showing enclosed yard. 9. Berkshire boar, recently acquired. 10. Berkshire boar, another newcomer. 11. Newborn animal treatment series. 12. Common hog at automatic feeder. 13. New arrival in litter of 15 pure blood Duroc pigsa SAFAP record. 14. Post natal treatments completed. Duroc-Jersey, first day. 15. Field farrowing house. 16. Farrowing building with kikuio grass pasturage in foreground. 17. Common sow, soon to farrow. 18. Pure Duroc boar, seven months old. 19. Newborn animal treatment series. Tying umbilical cord. 20. Duroc-Jersey sow and six week old offspring. The group has been removed from "Maternidade" to a field shelter. 21. Another view of Maternidade with shelter pen beyond. 22. Center aisle of Maternidade. 23. Maternidade. Pregnant sows are brought to this building a few days before time of delivery and remain there until several days after farrowing. 24. Duroc-Jerseys making most of conveniences of automatic drinking fixture. 25. Detail of Maternidade interior. Each stall is temporary home of new family. 26. Thatch roof makes ideal sun shelter for SAFAP porkers. 27. Self-feeder. Feed is put at top of these boxes and made easily available to stock at the feeding periods. 28. Self-feeders and hog shelter. 29. Butch, prize Duroc-Jersey boar, fathered most of the SAFAP population at Sao Carlos. 30. Several Duroc-Jersey families - pigs at two months - occupy comfortable quarters in field shelter. Young animals are ready for weaning. 31. Clipping needle teeth of newborn animal. Needle teeth impede proper feeding from sow. 32. Vaccinating newborn animal against enteritis. 33. Notching ear of newborn animal for information other than numbering. 34. Notching ear of newborn animal for numbering. 35. Two new additions to SAFAP population. 36. Duroc-Jersey sow and three day old litter. 37. This Duroc-Jersey mother of 15 established a record at Sao Carlos. All members of the family do not appear. 38. Manager Marra displays the success of SAFAP's experiment with Sudan grass. This fodder, imported from Texas, is planted with soy beans (near bottom) and has given exceptional results as an element of diet. 39. Part of equipment in use on Sao Carlo farm. 40. Inspection of newborn litter, day of birth. 41. Main farrowing housepurebred gilts, about 7 months. 42. Feed supplies for SAFAP stock in the growing stage. Hybrid corn with Sudan grass and soy beans between rowsmaternity barn in background. 43. Kiln and brick drying yard. Molding huts in background. 44. Farrowing house showing individual stalls. 45. The supply truck, shown here makes daily deliveries of water and fodder to installations in the farm's several sections. 46. Duroc-Jersey pigs, pictures are six months old, in excellent condition. 47. Disc breaking plow, with Ford tractor, part of machine equipment at Capao Bonito. 48. Farm equipment warehouse. This building is equipped with maintenance facilities. 49. Jeep and heavy duty disc plow. 50. Duroc-Jersey making most of conveniences of automatic drinking fixture. 51. Thatch roof makes ideal sun shelter for SAFAP porkers. 52. A new Duroc-Jersey family at home in Maternidade. 53. Butch - still behind his fence. 54. Second farrowing house. 55. Field shelter, automatic feeders, farrowing house in background.
    - SAFAP, Home Improvement (Box 5, Folder 122)
      56. SAFAP makes own bricks at CAPAO BONITO in kiln shown here. 57. Central group of buildings. Brick kiln and warehouse, machinery shelter, workers' houses. 58. Main workers' house. 59. Overseer's house. 60. Recently constructed duplex home for farm workers. 61. Dr. Ozanam Marra, SAFAP manager at Sao Carlo, in front of home reconstructed from one of the original barns. This house is equipped with electricity, running water and convenience unusual to similar housing in the countryside surrounding Sao Carlos.
    - SAFAP, Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 123)
      62. General view of SAFAP property looking from farm headquarters. 63. General view of farm headquarters - left to right: new duplex home for workers, well shelter, farm warehouse, old worker's quarters, manager's home. 64. General view of Sao Carlo farmnew duplex home for workers at left, farm warehouse in center, manager's home at right.
    - SAPS, Administration (Box 5, Folder 124)
      1. Representatives of AIA visit the mission of the American Franciscan Conventuals at Rua Caetano Martins 42, Rio de Janeiro, and are greeted by Father Julius d'Esutachio, of Perth Amboy, NJ. L to R: Father Julius, Miss Virginia Ortiz, AIA nutritionist in Rio, Dr. John B. Griffing, James Maddox, Henry Bagley, assistant public relations officer of AIA in Brazil. 2. At the SAPS kindergarten in Leblon, Rio de Janeiro, the children practice counting by placing blocks on a table, under the guidance of Senhorita Rocilda Pimentel. Watching them are Dr. John B. Griffing, Pres of AIA in BrazilJames G. Maddox, assistant director of AIA (NY), Miss Virginia Ortiz, AIA nutritionist in Rio, and Mrs. Eunice Peregrino, head of the Division of Home Visitors of SAPS. 3. Descending the "Morro de Kerosene" by a long flight of steps, a visiting party stops to rest. L to R: Father Julius d'Esutachio, of Perth Amboy, NJ, James G. Maddox, assistant director of AIA (NY), Miss Virginia Ortiz, AIA nutritionist in Rio, and Henry Bagley, assistant public relations officer of AIA in Brazil. 4. SAPS boy's club members from Kerosene Hill, Rio de Janeiro (l to r) Abel de S Souza Lopes and Jose Gregorio de Olegario, doing handicraft painting at the SAPS headquarters in Rio de Janeiro, while their teacher, Senhorita Cirene Alexandrino Barreto, explains their work to (l to r) Dr. John B. Griffing, Pres of AIA in BrazilMiss Virginia Ortiz, AIA nutritionist in Rio, James G. Maddox, assistant director of AIA (NY), and Mrs. Eunice Peregrino, head of the Division of Home Visitors of SAPS. 5. Mr. Hudgens visit to Brazil December 1949. 6. Mr. Hudgens visit to Brazil December 1949. 7. Mr. Hudgens visit to Brazil December 1949. 8. James G. Maddox, assistant director of AIA (NY), and Miss Virginia Ortiz, AIA nutritionist in Rio. 9. Miss Virginia Ortiz, AIA nutritionist in charge of training home visitors for SAPS, Julius d'Esutachio, Henry Bagley, assistant public relations officer of AIA in Brazil, and James G. Maddox, assistant director of AIA (NY). 10. Miss Virginia Ortiz, AIA nutritionist in Rio, Father Julius d'Esutachio, Franciscan friar, passing along the narrow path on kerosene Hill flanked by poor shacks. 11. Climbing the Morro do Kerosene in Rio de Janeiro to visit a school and clubhouse operated by the American Franciscan Conventuals are (l to r) Virginia Ortiz, AIA nutritionist in Rio, Father Julius d'Esutachio, Franciscan friar, and Henry Bagley, assistant public relations officer of AIA in Brazil. Three hill residents are passing them on the steep climb. 12. Mrs. Peregrino, head of the Division of Home Visitors of SAPS. Her husband, Major Umberto Peregrino, is director general of the organization. In the photo, behind Mrs. Peregrino, are Henry Bagley, assistant public relations officer of AIA in Brazil, and James Maddox, assistant director of AIA. 13. Dr. John B. Griffing, Pres of AIA in BrazilJames G. Maddox, assistant director of AIA (NY), talk with a house wife in the "favela" at Praia do Pinto (Pinto Beach), Leblon.
    - SAPS, Crafts (Box 5, Folder 125)
      14. Members of a SAPS girls' club at Victoria, state of Espirito Santo, Brazil, examining some of their handicraft work. 15. Members of a SAPS girls' club at Victoria, State of Espirito Santo, Brazil, displaying some of their handicraft work. 16. During Boys' Club meeting, Klabin District - Rio - Membership - 25, Ages 8 to 14. Art classes of a boy's club in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, organized under auspices of the government's social welfare program. 17. Young Girls' Club - Barreto District - Rio - Membership - 15, Ages 15 - 20. 18. SAPS club members living on Kerosene Hill, Rio de Janeiro, are taken daily to the SAPS headquarters at the Praca da Bandeira (Flag Square) to learn handicraft. Here are two of the boys (l to r) Abel de Souza Lopes and Jose Gregorio de Olegario, making practical use of their knack for painting. The others in the picture are (l to r) Dr. John B. Griffing, Pres of AIA in BrazilJames G. Maddox, assistant director of AIA (NY), and Senhorita Cirene Alexandrino Barreto, SAPS home visitor and teacher. Dr. Griffing and Maddox are examining tiles painted by the youngsters. 19. Girls of a SAPS club at the Klabin Factory, Rio de Janeiro, show some of their sewing work to James Maddox, assistant director of AIA (NY). 20. Flora Ferreira Batalha, member of a girls' club at the Klabin Factory, Rio de Janeiro, displays a gingham dress she made herself to Miss Virginia Ortiz, AIA nutritionist in charge of training home visitors for SAPS. The handicraft articles on the wall were made by members of the boys' clubs and girls' clubs at the factory. 21. Tiles painted by members of the SAPS boy's club of Kerosene Hill. 22. James Maddox, assistant director of AIA (NY) playfully teases one of the girls in the SAPS club sewing class at the Klabin Factory. 23. No caption. 24. No caption. 25. No caption.
    - SAPS, Education/Schools (Box 5, Folder 126)
      26. Two girls' Clubs meeting in SAPS club room at Fortaleza, Ceara. Membership - 22 in each club. 27. Seated: Senhorita Rocilda Pimentel, SAPS home visitor and teacher. Standing, l to r: Dr. John B. Griffing, Pres of AIA in BrazilJames G. Maddox, assistant director of AIA (NY), Virginia Ortiz, AIA nutritionist in Rio and Eunice Peregrino, head of the Division of Home Visitors of SAPS. 28. No caption.
    - SAPS, Gardening (Box 5, Folder 127)
      29. Senhorita Cleomar, SAPS home visitor, explains garden technique to a housewife at Natal, State of Rio Grande do Norte, Brazil. 30. An undergraduate of the Agnes Leith school for SAPS home visitors at Fortaleza, State of Ceara, Brazil, puts some of her learning to practical application in teaching members of a boys and girls' club how to plant a garden. 31. Boy's Planting First Club's Community Garden, Leblon, Rio. Planting a community vegetable garden in Leblon under the government's program to improve the food supply and nutrition of the working population. 32. Boys of the SAPS school in Leblon, giving final touches to a garden in which they will plant tomatoes and lettuce. 33. Boys of the SAPS school in Leblon, preparing the ground for a vegetable garden. 34. In the yard of the SAPS school in Leblon, young boys prepare the ground for a vegetable garden. Observing them are (l to r) Judite Martins, home visitor and teacher of SAPS, Miss Virginia Ortiz, AIA nutritionist in Rio, and Eunice Peregrino, head of the Division of Home Visitors of SAPS. 35. In the yard of the SAPS school in Leblon, young boys prepare the ground for a vegetable garden. Observing them are (l to r) Judite Martins, home visitor and teacher of SAPS, Miss Virginia Ortiz, AIA nutritionist in Rio, and Eunice Peregrino, head of the Division of Home Visitors of SAPS. 36. No caption.
    - SAPS, Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 128)
      37. A meeting of the housewives' club at Natal with Senhorita Cleomar, SAPS home visitor and club director. 38. Senhorita Cleomar with members of the SAPS housewives club at Nata. 39. Mother's Club - Leblon District - Rio. During enrollment of new members. 40. Mr. Hudgens' visit to Brazil, December 1949. 41. Children who live on Kerosene Hill gather around doorway of the nearly-finished school atop the hill. In shirtsleeves is James G. Maddox, assistant director of AIA (NY), Miss Virginia Ortiz, AIA nutritionist in Rio, Father Julius d'Esutachio, Franciscan friar who supervises the social work on the hill by the Conventual's mission. Club work at the school is to be conducted by a SAPS teacher and home visitor, whose training is guided by Miss Ortiz. 42. Residents of Kerosene Hill have to carry all their water up the hill, using ever handy oil can. Maddox and Ortiz stop to let them pass. 43. Atop the Morro de Kerosene stands the nearly completed concrete school and club building built by the Franciscan Conventuals, an American Mission near the base of the hill. To plan and carry out the club work, the friars asked the SAPS to send home a visitor, and SAPS agreed. Standing in the doorway are, l to r., Father Julius d'Esutachio, Franciscan friar, Miss Virginia Ortiz, AIA nutritionist in Rio, James Maddox, assistant director of AIA (NY). 44. Senhorita Maria Socorro Monteiro, home visitor of SAPS (seated) inscribed two neighborhood women in a SAPS women's club at the Klabin factory, while Mrs. Peregrino looks on. 45. Mrs. Peregrino, head of the Division of Home Visitors of SAPS and Miss Virginia Ortiz, AIA nutritionist in Rio, talk with a mother and daughter in front of their house in a shanty town in Leblon, Rio de Janeiro. The daughter is an enthusiastic member of the SAPA girls' club. 46. Mrs. Peregrino, head of the Division of Home Visitors of SAPS and Miss Virginia Ortiz, AIA nutritionist in Rio, talk with a mother and daughter in front of their house in a shant town in Leblon, Rio de Janeiro. The daughter is an enthusiastic member of the SAPS girls' club. 47. Part of the rhythm section of the band of the SAPS boys' club in Leblon, Rio de Janiero, playing a samba for the benefit of the AIA and SAPS visitors. 48. The band of the SAPS boy's club in Leblon strikes up a samba. 49. Children playing at the SAPS kindergarten in Leblon. All the children are of poor parents. Although primary education is theoretically compulsory, none of them would expect infantile education if the SAPS kindergarten did not exist. 50. View of Favela Kerozene (slum district) where first club house will be built for 4E (4H in US) work with boys and girls. 51. No caption.
    - SAPS, Nutrition (Box 5, Folder 129)
      52. Members of a SAPS housewives' club at Fortaleza after cooking "tutu," a Brazilian bean dish, with eggs, and tomatoes, under the supervision of a SAPS home visitor and club director. 53. Children of a SAPS club at Fortaleza are eating rice and tomatoes they have just cooked under the guidance of a SAPS club director. 54. Lunch time at Nursery School. 30 children, ages 3 - 6. Agnes June Leith School - Fortaleza, Ceara. 55. Young Brazilians learn some principles of nutrition, one of many activities of their club sponsored by the government's social welfare service in Rio de Janeiro. A US consultant provided by AIA helped to improve the training for personnel of this program. 56. Boy's Club - Klabin District - Rio, During Food Demonstration Membership - 20, Ages 8 to 14.
    - Miscellaneous, Cia T. Janer (Box 5, Folder 130)
      1. Warehouses - Sao Paulo. 2. Rio - Newsprint is moved by overhead crane. 3. Interior of Rio warehouse. 4. Rio - section of our store room for tool shed. 5. Rio - warehouse. 6. Rio - showrooms for marine motors - spare parts and accessories.
    - Miscellaneous, General (Box 6, Folder 131)
      1. No caption. 2. No caption.
    - Miscellaneous, Rio de Janeiro Slums (Box 6, Folder 132)
      1. Some of the houses of the "favela" (shanty-town) on the Morro do Kerozene (Kerosene Hill), Rio de Janeiro. 2. At the base of Kerosene Hill, Rio de Janeiro, the hill-dwellers wash their clothes and fill tin cans with water. There is no running water on the hill. 3. A small part of the "facela" on the Praia do Pinto (Pinto Beach) in Leblon, Rio de Janeiro. Many of the families in the "favela" work as handlers at the nearby horse-racing track, and many of their children belong to the SAPS clubs in Leblon. Tens of thousands of Rio's residents (total population of Rio: over two million) live in such squalor. 4. - 21. No caption.
  - Chile
    P/1027.3
    - Chile Education Program (Box 6, Folder 133)